Syed Kamran Hussain, Data Scientist

Houston, TX, 3462669221, s.kamranh@yahoo.com

PROFILE

From Cloud Engineer to Data Science, I love exploring new fields and I like challenging tasks with fruitful outcomes. I have 2+ years of experience as a Cloud Engineer, now I am devoted to moving ahead with exploring machine learning and data analytics. Check out my portfolio here.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jan 2021 - May 2022

Acting CTO, Virtalus LLC

Los Angeles

- Managed entire technical team, improved workflows and deliverables.
- Released managed Software as a Service model which covered new market segment.
- Developed CI/CD pipelines for automated updates and timely patches for entire infrastructure using Ansible and Gitlab CI/CD.
- Lead the team and contributed to fine tuning of Virtualization drivers and Storage stack, which significantly improved benchmark results.

Learn more.

Sep 2019 - Jan 2021

Cloud Support Engineer, Virtalus LLC

Los Angeles

- · Maintained private fork of open source projects, including maintaining releases and patches
- Maintained, designed and developed backup method in ruby using QEMU-API.
- Deployed, maintained, bootstraped servers in the Data Center.
- Improved current database and underlying data models, for even diverse data collection.

Learn more.

EDUCATION

Aug 2021 - Dec 2022

Masters of Data Science, University of St Thomas

Houston

- Explored Data Analytics and Data Models using R/Python.
- · Explored Machine learning and AI projects on Python using TensorFlow, Sklearn etc.
- In depth hands on of Data Visualization and Analytics.
- · Proficient in P-value testing, Power Calculations for datasets, ANOVA, Ethics.

Jul 2020 - Feb 2021

Master of Artificial Intelligence(Dropped due to Covid), RMIT

Melbourne, Australia

- Theoretical and Mathematical concepts of Machine Learning models and pipelines.
- Hands on educational projects on Deep learning following best practices.

Dec 2015 — Aug 2019

Computer and Information Systems Engineering, NED University

Karachi, Pakistan

I studied a wide range of courses and learned new skills during my bachelors, from Programing and Databases to Digital Signal Processing and Computer architecture. As my final project, I worked on a ride sharing app that helped me expand my knowledge in Android Studio(Java), Google Maps API, PHP, SQL.

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Mobile App Development

R/Matlab

SQL

Linux

Apache Spark/Hadoop

QEMU-KVM, and API

C++/Java/Ruby/Python/PHP

CI/CD Ansible

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Terraform

Raspberry Pi/Arduino

INTERNSHIPS

Apr 2022 - Jun 2022

Data Engineer, Otricath

Houston

Created and implemented data collection models and front end for their upcoming research study.